Sagar Bhardwaj

A creative tech brain with over 6 years of experience as a Fullstack Magento Developer. Able to write code while adhering to coding standards. Valuable team player with a track record of problem-solving and diagnosis.

dev.sagarbhardwaj@gmail.com (+91) 9717822270 Faridabad, Haryana, India linkedin.com/in/isagarbhardwaj github.com/isagarbhardwaj

EXPERIENCE

GlobalLogic, Gurugram — Senior Engineer (Adobe Commerce)

JULY 2023 - Present

LTIMindtree, **Noida** — Senior Software Engineer (Magento2)

JAN 2022 - JUNE 2023

Vamani Overseas, Faridabad — Software Engineer

DEC 2020 - JAN 2022

Solveda Software India Pvt Ltd, Gurugram — Software Developer

AUG 2020 - DEC 2020

Venture7, Faridabad — Software Engineer

FEB 2020 - APR 2020

Excellence Technologies Pvt Ltd, Noida — Web Developer

NOV 2017 - FEB 2020

EDUCATION

Maharshi Dayanand University, Rohtak — BCA

Bachelors in Computer Application 2014 - 2017

PROJECTS / Magento Extensions

Portfolio — Professional Developer's Portfolio Website Template

Created a fully responsive Developer's Portfolio template using basic react components and tailwind css to showcase my professional career path and skills.

Tools: Reactjs, Tailwind, GitHub Actions

Store Locator — Magento 2 Extension

Admin functionality to add physical store locations with integrated google map api.

Tools: Magento 2, Google Map API

Dealer Locator — Magento 2 Extension

Similar to **Store Locator**, but the customers signed up as **Dealer** while registration can add their physical store locations shown on frontend subjected to the admin approvals.

Tools: Magento 2, Google Map API, Inventory Management

SMS Notification — Magento 2 Extension

Allows the store admin to be able to send SMS notifications to the customers on several events like Order creation, Signup, Login, etc. using **Twilio**, **MSG91** and **Textlocal** APIs.

Tools: Magento 2, API Integration

Store Pickup — Magento 2 Extension

Customers can select one of the store locations at the checkout page defined by admin, to pick up their orders.

Tools: Magento 2, Admin Configurations

SKILLS

Technologies: PHP, Adobe Commerce Cloud, React Js

Designing: Css, Less, Bootstrap

Version control: Github, Bitbucket, GitLab

Project Mgmt. : Jira, Github

Well practised: HTML, CSS, LESS, JQuery and Javascript.

OS known: Windows, Ubuntu, MacOS

Others: Zendesk

EXPERTISE

- Multi-Store Development
- Payment Gateway Integration
- Theme Development
- Third-Party API Integration
- Speed Optimization
- Extension (Module) Development
- Social Login Implementation

- Troubleshooting and Bug Fixing
- Checkout Customisation
- Magento 1.x upgrade to Magento 2.x
- Responsive web designs using
- LESS CSS & Bootstrap
- GraphQL implementation
- Inventory Management